撃て！
（グリフィス）俺はグリフィス
I'm Griffith. What's your name?
お前 名は？
Guts.
（ガッツ）ガッツ
一体ここは…？
Where am I?
（グリフィス）鷹の団
The Band of the Hawk.
I will get my own kingdom...
俺は 俺の国を手に入れる
ガッツ お前の死に場所は
俺が決めてやる
Guts... I'll be the one to decide
the place where you'll die.
（国王）おらぬのか…
Isn't there anyone who can stop
those black devils of Chuder?
チューダーの黒い悪魔を倒す者は…
やめろ！
No!
He is my...my...
そいつは俺の…
俺の…
（ゾッド）
この男の野望が潰えるとき―
When his ambition dies within him...
death will come to you!
貴様に死が訪れる
決して逃れられぬ死が！
A death you cannot escape!
A Behelit.
ベヘリット
これを持つ者は
自分の血と肉を引き替えに―
She said it's the destiny of one
who holds it to acquire the world...
in exchange for his flesh and blood.
世界を手に入れる運命なんだって
（ガッツ）殺し？
Kill who?
Will you do it?
（グリフィス）頼まれてくれるか？
（ガッツ）しのごの言わずに
命令すりゃいいんだ
Just give me an order
like you always do.
いつも通りに
生まれてしまったから
仕方なく ただ生きる
To simply live a life
because one was born into it...
I can't accept that.
そんな生き方 俺には耐えられない
決して人の夢に
すがったりはしない
A friend is someone who
does not cling to another's dream.
He decides his own dream.
自分の生きる理由は自らが定め
その夢を踏みにじる者があれば―
and he will stand against anyone...
who dares to trample on it
with his body and soul.
全身全霊をかけて立ち向かう
Even if that person is me.
たとえそれが この私でも…
私にとって友とは そんな
“対等の者”だと思っています
A friend to me. is an equal.
（グリフィス）生まれてしまったから
仕方なく ただ生きる
To simply live a life
because one was born into it...
そんな生き方 俺には耐えられない
I can't accept that...
（国王）さすがだな 鷹の団は
The Band of the Hawk is
most impressive.
（ラバン）はい 右翼の敵を
彼らだけで釘付けにしています
Yes, they are single-handedly shutting down
the enemy's right flank.
（国王）
グリフィス とんだ拾い物よ
Griffith... He was a good find.
（重臣１）
ユリウス殿下さえご存命なら
If only Count Julius were alive...
（重臣２）我が軍は
翼の片方をもがれた形だ
Our army is like a bird
with only one wing.
The Band of the Hawk will make
themselves even more indispensable...
（重臣３）これで ますます
鷹の団の重要性は…
こんな時に
Not at a time like this...!
（アドン）ふふはは～
So you're her!
貴様かあ 鷹の団の
女千人長というのは あ？
The woman who commands
a thousand of the Band of the Hawk!
フン 女の分際で
騎士の真似事などしおって…
A woman playing at being a knight...
Perhaps you got
your rank of commander
どうせ その千人長の地位も―
by crawling into Griffith's bed, right?
あのグリフィスとやらのしとねに
潜り込んで手に入れたのだろう？
貴様～！
You bastard!
（アドン）でやっ
うらぁ
The battlefield is
the sacred ground of men!
女の身でありながら戦場という
男の聖域に踏み込んだ浅はかさ…
How dare a woman set foot upon it!
この青鯨(せいげい)超重装猛進撃滅騎士団団長
アドン様が知らしめてくれるわ！
I, Adon, head of the Blue Whale
Ultra Heavy Armored
Fierce Assault Annihilation
Knight Corps
shall teach you the folly
of your actions!
（鷹の団員１）姐さん！
Big Sis!
Commander Casca!
（鷹の団員２）キャスカ千人長！
（キャスカ）バカ！ 来るな！
Idiots! Stay back!
Spineless fools who allow themselves
to be led by a woman!
（アドン）
女におもねる腑抜けどもが！
ハッ 女の尻に敷かれてるだけあって
歯応えのない！
Can't even put up a fight... Not surprising
since you let a woman order you around!
フン ハッ そらっ！
Take this!
どうした そこまでか？
What's the matter?
Is that all you've got?
そのザマで千人長とは笑止千万！
鷹の団も よほど人手不足とみえる
It's a joke that they call you
the commander of a thousand.
The Band of the Hawk really scraped
the bottom of the barrel.
ほう？ 見ればなかなかの器量…
You're not so bad-looking.
ふーむ
I'll overlook your earlier insolence.
今までの非礼は許そう
どうだ チューダーに来んか？
What do you say?
Come to Chuder.
何？
What?!
（アドン）千人長に迎えよう
You shall have a thousand...
我がチューダー兵
千人を慰める千人長にな
I'll give you
a thousand Chuder soldiers,
so you can keep them warm.
ガーハッハッハ
下衆が！
You bastard!
（アドン）嫌か？
No?
ならば… 死ね！
Well then, die!
Huh?
Guts!
ガッツ！
This isn't like you...
（ガッツ）らしくねえなァ
き… 貴様
You bastard!
（ガッツ）来いよ 誰でもいい
Anyone will do. Come on.
I feel like swinging this
as hard as I can.
こいつを思いっきり
ブン回したい気分なんだ
（アドン）むー よくぞ受けたな小僧
だが まぐれは二度続かん！
So you countered, eh kid.
Not bad.
But that was just a lucky break!
My ultimate spear technique
has been passed down
我がコボルイッツ家140年にわたり
伝承されし戦槍術 最大奥義
through the Coborlwitz family
for over 140 years!
Take my ultimate secret technique!
くらえ 岩斬(がんざん)旋風…！
Ganzansenpu!
岩斬旋風… 何よ？
Ganzansenpu...
What the hell is that?
What's the matter?
どうした
いつものお前らしくないぜ
This isn't like you.
気ィ抜いてると…
If you're not alert...
おっ おい！
H-Hey!
キャスカ！
Casca!
おい しっかりしろ！
キャス…
Hey!
Snap out of it...
Cas...!
しまっ…
Damn!
ヒャッハァ！
（ガッツ）ぐわぁ！
- Big Sis!
- Captain!
（団員たち）
姐さん！ 隊長！ ガッツ！
Guts!
（ジュドー）ガッツ！
Casca!
キャスカーッ
（ガッツ）ぐっ がはっ
ハァ うえっ
クソッ 二度と
こんなカッコで泳ぐか！
Damn it...
I'm never swimming
in this get up again!
She's burning up!
ひでえ熱だ こりゃあ…
このまま雨ざらしじゃ
まずいな どこか…
We can't stay in this rain.
Gotta find somewhere...
ガッツとキャスカが？
Guts and Casca?!
（ジュドー）あの高さじゃヤバいぞ
しかもガッツは撃たれてる
From that height,
who knows what happened to them.
On top of which,
Guts was wounded.
早く捜索隊を
We need to dispatch
a search party now!
Count Griffith, we are at war.
（将軍１）
グリフィス卿 今は戦時
I adamantly oppose weakening
our formation for two mere soldiers.
たかが二人の兵卒ごときに
戦力を割くなど 言語道断
（将軍２）噂に高い切り込み隊長と
女千人長なら―
They are the highly touted Captain
of the Raiders
and the female commander
of a thousand, correct?
Surely, they can find
their way back on their own.
自力で戻ってこられるでしょう
I am in total agreement.
（将軍３）いや まったく
とりあえず 濡れた服だけでも…
Well, I'll take off whatever's soaked.
だいたい熱出したまま戦なんて…
She kept on fighting
even though she had a fever.
これだから女ってのは…
That's why women are so...
ん？ このバカ どっかケガを…
Huh?
The idiot... She's hurt!
So that's it.
そういうことか
大変だな 女ってのは…
Must be rough being a woman.
（キャスカ）ハァ ハァ ハァ
Wait!
（ヴェルノー）待て
君に守るものがあるなら
その剣を取れ
If you have something to protect.
take up that sword.
Hey.
よう
Where are we?
ここは？
（ガッツ）川っぺりの洞窟さ
運良く 川に落ちたんで助かったんだ
A cave by the river.
Luckily, falling into
the river saved us.
ん… 川？
Uh...river?
バカ まだ横になってろ
熱が下がりきってねーんだからよ
Hey! Lie down, stupid!
Your fever hasn't dropped yet.
しょーがねーだろ
I had no choice.
ずぶ濡れで おまけに
凍えかけてたんだからよ
You were soaking wet
and freezing to death.
…んだよ その目は ホラ
Don't look at me like that.
Here...
ハーッ お前… うおっ
何すんだ てめェ
What the hell was that for?!
ちょっと待て おいっ
Hey, stop!
Hey, you-!
てめえ いい加減に…
Why you-!
てんめェ いい加減にしやがれ
このヒス女ァ
Why you... Cut it out, you bitch!
こっちは死ぬ思いで てめえを
川から引きずり上げたんだぞ
I risked my life to pull you
out of the river!
女じゃなかったら
ブン殴って顎外してるとこだぜ
If you weren't a woman,
I'd punch you and knock your jaw out!
女…
A "woman"...
ったく すぐ頭に
血ィのぼりやがって
Damn it, flipping out like that.
これだから女にゃ
戦仕事は向かねえっつーの
That's why women
don't belong on the battlefield.
おい
Hey!
私だって
好きで女に生まれたわけじゃない
I didn't ask...to be born a woman.
情けない お前だけには…
助けられたくなかった
This is pitiful!
You're the only one
I didn't want to be saved by!
You're the only one...
お前だけには…
（ガッツ）まだ体が…
You're still not well.
随分と嫌われたもんだぜ
…ったく
You really hate me, don't you...
damn it?
（キャスカ）覚えているか？
Do you remember?
あの日 あの丘でグリフィスが
お前にかけた言葉…
What Griffith said to you that day,
on the hill?
お前が欲しいんだ ガッツ
I want you. Guts.
Yeah.
グリフィスは 誰にも
あんなことは言いはしなかった
Griffith has never said
that to anyone else.
Not before, and not since.
今まで誰にも…
なぜだ？ どうして
お前でなければならないんだ？
Why is that?!
Why did it have to be you?
どうして…
Why?
私があの人の剣(つるぎ)になりたかったのに
I wanted to be...
his sword.
そうか
I see...
So that's your dream.
それがお前の夢か…
（捜索隊１）
おい ほんとにこの辺りなのか？
Hey, are you sure they're around here?
（捜索隊２）ああ 間違いねえよ
Yeah, I'm sure of it.
くたばってんじゃねえのか？
あの崖から落ちたんじゃ…
You sure they're not dead?
They fell off that cliff, after all.
（捜索隊１）死体でも
報奨金は出すって アドン様が
Sir Adon said he'd pay
the bounty even for their corpses.
（捜索隊２）
もうちょい 川下あさってみるか
Let's look a little further downstream.
のんびりしてるヒマはねえな
There's no time to waste.
お前は… どうなんだ
What about you?
Why do you...
お前は なぜ戦っている
fight?
Don't talk. You need to
save your strength.
しゃべるな 体力を消耗するぞ
俺は…
I...
（アドン）ハーッハハハ
見つけたぞ 小僧ども
I found you brats!
（ガッツ）よう！
Hey! You're looking lively, old man!
元気そうだな オッサン
あいつ…
It's him!
Impudence!
ぬかせ 貴様はただでは殺さんぞお
I'm not just going to kill you!
我がコボルイッツ家200年にわたり
伝えられし拷問術
I'll administer the torture technique
passed down through the Coborlwitz family
for two hundred years...
The hundred-year convulsive death...
悶絶百年殺しで この世の地獄を
たっぷり見せてくれるわ！
...and show you what hell
on earth is all about.
女はこの場で
傭兵どものエサにしてやる
I'll leave the woman here for
the mercenary soldiers to feast on!
I don't think that's a good idea.
（ガッツ）そいつあ やめといた方が
いいんじゃねえの？
こいつはおっかねえぞォ
食いちぎられるぞ
She's pretty vicious.
She'll bite it off!
ぬうう なめくさって かかれ！
Such insolence!
Get them!
I'll get up front.
（ガッツ）俺が前に出る
お前は一気に森を駆け上がれ
Make a run for it straight
into the forest!
Huh?
（ガッツ）
今だ ボケッとしてんじゃねえっ
Now! Move it!
ふざけるな
私一人だけ逃げるなんて！
Don't be ridiculous!
I'm not going to run off alone!
Don't get me wrong!
（ガッツ）勘違いしてんじゃねえ！
病み上がりは足手まといなんだよ
The sick will only get in my way!
弓隊 あの女を狙え！
Archers! Aim for the woman!
はなてぇ～
Fire!
Guts!
ガッツ！
（アドン）だーはっはっ バカめ
What a fool.
一度ならず二度までも
たかが女のために
Sacrificing himself not once,
but twice for a woman.
Why... Why?!
どうして どうして？
剣ってのは鞘に収まるもんだろ
A sword returns to its sheath.
Huh?
（ガッツ）帰んな 剣の主の元へ
グリフィスのところへ よ
Go home to your sword master.
Go to Griffith.
I'll think about an answer
to your question earlier.
俺は… さっきの答えを考えとくぜ
（アドン）
恐れるな 相手はたった二人！
Do not fear!
There are only two of them!
Surround them and attack at once!
囲んで一気に行けい！
行け！ グズグズするな 行け！
Go!
Don't just stand there! Go!
I swear I'll return with the others.
仲間を連れて必ず戻る
それまで…
Until then...
死ぬな！
don't die!
Don't let the woman get away!
（アドン）女を逃がすな！ 殺せ！
Kill her!
女のケツを追っかけるのは
仕事の後にしな
You can go chase after girls...
after you finish your job.
Don't die!
死ぬな…
（アドン）
ハーハッハッ 左手が死んだぞ
His left hand is useless!
He won't be able swing that
ridiculously big sword anymore!
これでそのバカでかい剣も
振るえまい
（ガッツ）
面白くなってきたじゃねーか
This is getting interesting...
（敵兵１）でやっ
（敵兵１）へへっ
手間かけてくれたな 姉ちゃん
You sure caused us
a lot of trouble, girl.
このっ！
Why you-!
Just give up.
諦めな
（キャスカ）
なんて非力なんだ この腕は…
Why am I so...weak?!
Don't even think about
biting your tongue.
（敵１）舌なんて噛もうと思うなよ
ここで死なれちゃつまんねェからな
I want you to be alive for this.
帰んな 剣の主の元へ
Go back to your sword master.
舌など噛まん
I won't bite my tongue.
だが…―
I won't let you have your way
with me either!
貴様を上に乗せるつもりもない！
（敵兵２）てめえ！
Why you-!
You bitch!
（敵兵３）この野郎！
無事か キャスカ
Are you all right, Casca?
（キャスカ）急いで！
Hurry!
ガッツは私を逃がすために
一人で敵中に残ったんだ
Guts stayed back with the enemy...
so I could escape!
出られるヤツは みんな出せ
Send every man available!
What the hell am I doing...?
（ガッツ）何やってるんだ 俺は…
こんな くだらねェところで
In a stupid place like this...
安っぽく―
risking my life...
命張って…
so cheaply?
（グリフィス）誰のためでもない
A dream he must realize for himself.
and himself alone.
自分が
自分自身のために成す 夢です
生まれてしまったから
仕方なく ただ生きる
To simply live a life
because one was born into it...
そんな生き方 俺には耐えられない
I can't accept that.
私にとって友とは そんな
“対等の者”だと思っています
A friend to me...
is...an equal.
貴様ら それでもチューダーの…
You call yourselves men of Chuder?!
ぐわあ～ ああ…
（ガッツ）考えてる暇はねえ
There's no time to think...
Right now. all there is...
is how to cut...
今はどう斬るか どう殺すか
how to kill...
それだけだ
That's all there is.
I hope we make it in time!
（キャスカ）間に合ってくれ
ここだ！
Over here!
すげえ…
Amazing...
（ガストン）これ全部 隊長が…？
Did the Captain do all this?
No way. There must be
close to a hundred...
（ジュドー）
冗談だろ 百人近くいるぜ
（グリフィス）ガッツ いるか？
Guts, are you here?
返事をしろ ガッツ！
Answer me, Guts!
（キャスカ）ガッツ！
Guts!
（団員１）隊長！
Captain!
（団員２）ガッツ隊長！
Captain Guts!
（団員３）おい
Hey...
（団員４）やべえんじゃねえのか
This doesn't look good...
Guts! Hey!
ガッツ！ おい
死ぬなって言ったろ
I told you not to die!
Are you breaking
your promise to me?!
お前は私との約束を破るのか！
ガッツ
Guts...!
（ガッツ）うっせーなー
Shut up!
ゆするんじゃねえ
Don't shake me.
傷にしみんだろうが
It makes my wounds hurt.
ガッツ
Guts...
（団員５）すげーや
Amazing!
隊長 バケモンだぜ
Man, the Captain's a monster.
（団員６）まさか負けるとは
思ってなかったろうな
These guys probably didn't think
that they could lose.
痛っ 痛い
Ouch! Ouch!
鷹の団に百人斬りの
ガッツあり！ だな
The Band of the Hawk has
the "Guts" to slay a hundred men!
Captain Guts who slew
a hundred men!
（団員７）
百人斬りガッツ隊長ーッ！
- Hurrah!
Release!
（上官）はなて
（隊長）なんということだ
誰一人取りつけんとは…
I can't believe this.
Not a single man can get close.
恐るべしドルドレイ
No wonder Doldrey is so feared.
紫犀(しさい)聖騎士団だ！
ボスコーンが来るぞ
It's the Holy Purple Rhino Knights!
Boscogn is coming!
Their defense is impregnable and
any enemy is easily repelled.
（ラバン）
鉄壁の防御で敵を弾き返し―
Then the exhausted forces
come under assault
疲弊したところをチューダー最強と
謳われる紫犀聖騎士団で殲滅する
by the Holy Purple Rhino Knights,
reputedly Chuder's strongest.
この大胆不敵な戦法の前に―
As a result of this audacious tactic,
the loss to our army,
我が軍の損失は
精鋭･白虎騎士団を含め―
including our elite White Tiger Knights,
has climbed to 30%.
約三割に上ります
これ以上の損失は…
Any more losses...
（将軍１）
そんなことは わかっておる！
We know that already!
もとよりドルドレイは
我がミッドランド古来の要害
Doldrey was long
a stronghold of Midland.
Of course, it cannot
be penetrated easily.
そう易々とは落とせん
（将軍２）チューダーは今
皇位継承を巡る内乱の危機にある
There is internal conflict in Chuder
over the next succession to the throne.
この地にいつまでも
戦力を割く余力はない
They do not have the reserves
to focus on a battle here...
このまま長期戦になれば
おのずと…
If this becomes
a long, drawn-out battle...
（将軍３）いやはや悠長な…
Enough discussion.
ドルドレイは
チューダー最後の橋頭堡(きょうとうほ)
Doldrey is Chuder's last foothold.
ヤツらを駆逐し―
We must defeat Chuder and
end this Hundred Years' War now...
この百年戦争を終結させるのは
今をおいてほかありません
This is the time to do it!
（将軍４）左様
これは千載一隅の好機ですぞ
He is right.
This is our one-in-a-thousand chance.
（将軍１）いや しかし…
But...
うーむ…
苦しいのはチューダーとて同じはず
総力戦への諸卿の考えは？
Chuder is suffering as well.
My generals, how do you feel
about total warfare?
（将軍５）私は反対です
I am opposed.
逃亡兵が後を絶たぬほど
兵どもの志気は低下しております
Morale is low and
men are deserting like flies.
With the White Tiger Knights annihilated...
ましてや白虎騎士団まで
壊滅したとあっては
（将軍２）国内の残存勢力も
まだ掃討できてはおりません
Also, we still have remnant enemy
forces to deal with in our territories.
万が一 敵に背後を
突かれることがあれば―
If the enemy should attack
from the rear,
the situation will be irreparable.
取り返しのつかない事態に
なりましょうぞ
（将軍６）これ以上遠征が長引けば
再度 戦費調達の必要に迫られます
If this military expedition continues,
there will be need for
additional defense funds.
たび重なる課税に
民衆の不満が高まるのは…
More taxation will burden
the citizens...
（将軍７）さすがの鷹殿も
今回ばかりは お手上げでしょうな
- and lead to unrest...
- Even you must consider this situation...
a dilemma, Sir Hawk.
（グリフィス）ご命令とあらば
If I were so ordered...
いや それも致し方ないこと いかに
戦の申し子と謳われようとも… え？
Well, that's to be expected.
Even for a genius of warfare
such as yourself...
What?
陛下のご命令とあらば
If His Majesty so ordered me...
うーむ
There is no need for a large force.
大軍はいりません 鷹の団のみで
当たらせていただきます
The Band of the Hawk
will take this on.
今 何と？
- What did you-?!
- What?!
（将軍２）バカな！ あのドルドレイを
鷹の団だけでどうやって？
Ridiculous!
The Band of the Hawk to
recapture Doldrey by themselves?!
Even the White Tiger Knights
were annihilated...
白虎騎士団すらやられたのだぞ
気は確かですか？
Are you in your right mind?!
We are talking about
a mere 5,000 on horseback
たかだか五千の騎兵で
三万の敵を相手にするのですよ
against an army 30,000 strong!
Ridiculous! This is the foolish talk
of a novice!
（将軍５）バカバカしい！
若造のたわ言だ
（将軍２）この百年 歴代の名将が
叶わなかったドルドレイ攻略を―
Over these one hundred years,
countless distinguished generals
have attempted and failed
to conquer Doldrey.
鷹の団だけで
果たせるわけがない
The Band of the Hawk cannot manage
such a feat alone!
グリフィス卿
まこと… なのだな？
Sir Griffith, was that sincere?
I command the Band of the Hawk
to capture Doldrey!
鷹の団に
ドルドレイ攻略を命ずる
（ボスコーン）鷹の団が？
The Band of the Hawk?!
（兵士）はい 騎兵約五千をもって
こちらに向かっております
Yes. Roughly 5,000 of them
are headed this way.
（ボスコーン）たった五千で
このドルドレイを落とすと？
They expect to take Doldrey
with a mere 5,000?
一体ヤツらは…
What do they...?
（ゲノン）ボスコーン将軍
General Boscogn...
Yes?
（ゲノン）白い鷹のグリフィス…
ヤツを殺してはならん
Griffith the White Hawk must
not be killed.
Huh?
（ゲノン）鷹は生かしたまま
ここに連れてくるのだ よいな？
Bring the Hawk here alive.
Understand?
（ボスコーン）しかし―
But...
As long as he is alive,
the Band of the Hawk...
ヤツが生きている限り 鷹の団…いや
ミッドランドの勢いを止めることは
Rather, the momentum of
Midland cannot be stopped.
ボスコーン将軍！
General Boscogn!
よいな？
Understood?
Yes, sir.
（コルカス）
ったく どっから攻めろってんだよ
Damn it... How are we supposed
to attack?
（ジュドー）後ろは断崖絶壁
最新式の大筒がおよそ二十門
The back of it is a cliff...
They've got 20 of
the latest catapults.
On top of that,
あとは矢と油と
石の雨ってとこかな
we'll be rained upon with arrows,
hot oil and rocks.
とりあえず正面から
攻める以外ないなあ
We have no choice
but to attack from the front.
（リッケルト）しかも
あの紫犀聖騎士団もいるんだよね…
And there's the Holy Purple
Rhino Knights too, right?
We can win, can't we?
（ガストン）
勝てますよね 俺たち
ガッツ？
Guts?
Huh?
なーに ちいとばかし
城がでかいだけだって
The fortress is a little big, so what?
いつもの通りグリフィスの
言うようにやりゃあ勝てる な？
Just do what Griffith says
and it will be ours.
Right?
（副将）どういうつもりだ
What are they planning?
川を背に陣を敷くとは
ヤツは兵法を知らんのか？
Setting up formation with
the river behind them?
Don't they know anything
about military strategy?
（ボスコーン）どのような奇策を
弄したところで―
Whatever it is,
considering the size of their force,
あの数では所詮
一時しのぎにしかなるまい
it's just a desperate tactic.
正面から堂々と討つのみ
We will take them straight on,
nothing else.
Yes, sir!
グリフィス
Griffith...
待っておったぞ
I've been waiting for you.
（門衛）
アドン将軍 よくご無事で
General Adon,
I'm glad to see you well.
（アドン）うむ
留守の間
変わったことはなかったか？
Anything happen in my absence?
（グリフィス）行けるか？
Are you ready?
第一陣 前へ
Vanguard...onward!
Draw your swords!
抜刀！
第一陣 出撃！
Vanguard, attack!
（伝令兵）敵が動きました！ 第一陣は
グリフィス卿直属部隊ほか約二千
The enemy is on the move!
Count Griffith himself leads
the vanguard.
The rest number roughly 2000.
（ボスコーン）寡兵をさらに
二つに分けたというのか？
He's divided his already
small army into two?
（副将）
しかも大将 自らが先陣とは…
With the General himself
at the fore?
Interesting, let us take him on.
面白い 受けてやろう
先鋒出撃 敵第一陣を壊滅せよ
Call up the advance guard!
Destroy the enemy's first wave!
Follow the captain!
（鷹の団員）隊長に続け！
No way! We can't stop them!
（チューダー兵１）
バカな 止まらない
（チューダー兵２）我ら
紫犀聖騎士団が押されてるだと？
Our Holy Purple Rhino Knights
are being pushed back!
The enemy is too fast!
（チューダー兵３）敵が速すぎる
（副将）しょ… 将軍！
敵が向かってきます
G-General!
The enemy is approaching.
（ボスコーン）うろたえるな！
Do not panic!
軽騎兵の機動力を生かし
一点突破を狙う策か…
He's taking advantage of
the mobility of a light cavalry
to force through our line.
Put our heavy cavalry directly
before the enemy.
敵 前面に重騎兵
両翼に弓隊を展開せよ
And archers, commence attack
from both flanks!
鷹め どう出る
What will you do now, Hawk?
敵も冷静じゃねえか
The enemy is calm!
隊列を分断するつもりか！
They're trying to make us scatter!
Damn Boscogn! What is he doing?
（ゲノン）
ボスコーンめ 何をやっておる
あれではグリフィスを殺しかねんぞ
Griffith could very well be killed.
Vanguard! Fall back!
第一陣撤退 本陣まで下がれ
Return to the main force!
Go straight through them!
野郎ども ずらかれ！
W-What?
（チューダー兵）
何だ？ 戻ってくるぞ
They're coming back!
ぐわっ
（副将）
敵が敗走していきます！
The enemy is retreating.
I can't figure it out.
解せぬな このような攻め方
最初から結果は見えていたはず
He should have anticipated
this result from the very start.
これが常勝無敗の鷹の団
白い鷹だと…？
This is the Band of the Hawk
who knows only victory.
The White Hawk, no less.
What are you doing,
General Boscogn...?
（ゲノン）
何をしておる ボスコーン将軍
（ボスコーン）ゲノン総督…
Governor General!
（ゲノン）敵は敗走していくぞ
みすみす勝機を逃す気か？
The enemy is retreating.
Will you let victory slip out
of our hands?
は… しかし…
No...well...
皆に告げる 敵大将 白い鷹の
グリフィスを捕らえた者には―
Listen, everyone!
A reward of your asking
awaits anyone
who captures the enemy general,
the White Hawk!
思いのままの褒美をとらす！
ただし…―
However, he must be taken unharmed!
必ず無傷で捕らえるのだ よいな！
Understood?
（ボスコーン）総督
Governor General! It is unwise to
make such a lofty promise to soldiers.
そのようなことを軽々しく
約束されては兵どもの押さえが…
They will be uncontroll-
（ゲノン）
ボスコーン将軍 大儀であった
General Boscogn...
Thank you for your service
今よりはこのゲノンが指揮を執る
貴公ら紫犀聖騎士団は―
I, Gennon, will be taking command.
Your Holy Purple Rhino Knights
will henceforth
青鯨黒狼 そして我が蛇蠍(じゃかつ)猛攻騎士団と
ともに敵を追撃し―
join the Blue Whale, Black Wolf,
and my Scorpion Serpent Assault
Knights in pursuing the enemy,
速やかにグリフィス卿を捕らえよ
and to swiftly capture Griffith.
But what about defending the fortress?!
（副将）これでは城の防備が…
（ゲノン）どうした
What is the matter?
命令が聞こえんのか
ボスコーン将軍？
Did you not hear my order,
General Boscogn?
General...
将軍…
We have no choice.
やむをえん
だが鷹は生け捕らず殺せ
However, kill the Hawks without fail.
これ以上 ヤツを
のさばらすわけにはいかぬ
We cannot allow them to
have free rein any longer.
Yes, sir!
（ボスコーン）
これより敵追撃を開始する！
We will begin pursuit of the enemy!
ヘヘヘ… あれ…―
Are we supposed to...
take on all of them?
全部 相手にしようっての？
俺たち…
陣形を整えろ！
Take formation!
The river is behind us.
We have no escape route!
後ろは川 逃げ場はない！
Lay down your lives...
命を捨てろ！
それ以外に生き残る道はない
There's no other chance
for survival!
If we do survive,
we will stand victorious!
生き残れば
俺たちの勝ちだ！
てやーっ
クソッ！ クソッ！
Damn it!
The enemy force is small.
（ボスコーン）敵は少数
小細工をさせる前に追い落とせ！
Mow them down
before they have a chance to
pull any cheap tricks!
Damn it! It's no good!
ちきしょー もうダメだ！
（リッケルト）溺れて死ぬくらいなら
戦った方がましだよっ！
I'd rather die fighting than
drown in some river!
はは リッケルトちゃんが
キレやがった んがぁ～っ！
Little Rickert's lost it!
（ボスコーン）貴様は？
You are?
Guts, the Captain of the Raiders,
from the Band of the Hawk.
鷹の団切り込み隊長 ガッツ！
（見張り兵１）何にも見えんぞ
どうなってんだ あっちは？
I can't see a thing.
What's going on out there?
（見張り兵２）気にするこたぁねえよ
結果なんざ わかりきってんだし
Don't even bother worrying.
The outcome is obvious.
そんなことより いつんなったら
酒にありつけんだろうなァ
I'm more interested in when
we'll get some booze around here.
敵の大将 捕らえたもんには
好きな褒美が出るってのに
The one who snares the enemy general
will get any reward he asks for...
ったく とんだ貧乏くじ
引いたもんだぜ…
and I get stuck with this stupid duty.
何だ？ どうした
What? What's the matter?
あ… あれは
て… 敵の別働隊だっ！
Th-That's...
That's a different enemy force!
（チューダー兵）
おい 何か様子が変だぞ
Hey, something's strange...
あっ アドン様 城内に侵入者です
Sir Adon, we have intruders
in the castle!
Hurry!
（キャスカ）急げ！
よし 急いで門を封鎖しろ
敵の伝令を城外に出すな！
All right! Hurry and close the gates!
Do not allow messengers to leave!
The Barbier and Benoit troops
will do as planned
バルビエ隊 ベノワ隊は
作戦通りに残った敵を制圧しろ
and subdue all remaining
enemy troops!
Every second counts!
一刻を争うぞ！
Griffith was right about everything.
すべてグリフィスの情報通りだ
さすがだな
You got to hand it to him.
（団員）姐さ… ん
Big Sis!
フン！ 女の浅はかさよのう
Such a foolish woman.
そう簡単に 事が運ぶと思ったら
大間違いだ
You're making a big mistake
if you think things
will go your way so easily.
今度こそ容赦せんぞ
I'll show you no mercy this time!
（団員）キャスカ千人長！
Commander Casca!
手出しするな
Don't interfere!
こいつは あたしがやる！
I'll deal with him myself!
（アドン）ぬう～
ほざけ！
You fool!
W-Wow...
（団員）すごい…
He's strong...
強え…
What is taking Boscogn so long?
（ゲノン）
ボスコーンめ 何を手間取っておる
ひるむな 押し返せ！
Don't let up. Push them back.
Oh...!
ぎゃああ ああ～っ
な なぜだ 前とは別人のような
その太刀筋…
H-How?
You're fighting like
a different person!
As long as I'm physically sound,
I'd never lose to a bastard like you!
体調さえ万全なら
貴様ごときに負ける私ではない
（団員）くう～
やっぱ 姐さんすげェや！
Big Sis really is incredible!
ここはいい
お前たちは準備を急げ！
I've got this under control.
Hurry with the preparations!
（団員たち）はい！
- Right!
この…
ガッツ！
Guts!
さてはボスコーンめ
Well then, Boscogn...
さっきまでの勢いは
どこにいったのかな？
What happened to the fighting spirit
you had earlier?
ほ～ら 腕が下がってきたぞ
剣の重さに耐えられんか…？
Hey, your arm is dropping!
Is your sword too heavy for you?
フン 減らず口も出んとみえる
You can't even muster a retort.
むうっ？ 貴様は切り込み隊長
Hey, it's the Captain of the Raiders!
なんてね！
Just kidding!
どうだあっ 我がコボルイッツ家
千年にわたり 伝えられし撹乱術
How was that?
The Coborlwitz Family Distraction
Technique, honed over 1000 years.
You fell right for it!
まんまと引っかかりおったわ！
（団員１）姐さん！
（団員２）キャスカ千人長
- Big Sis!
- Commander Casca!
Stay out of this!
いいから手を出すな！
（アドン）
フン！ 意地を張りおって
Such pride!
部下たちの目の前で
慰みものにされても―
I wonder if you'll still be proud
when I amuse myself with you
before your men.
まだ強がっていられるかな？
I'm going to get a good taste
of your soft skin.
その柔肌 たっぷりと
味わわせてもらおう
お前にほんとの女の喜びを
教えてやる
I shall teach you what true joy
is to a woman.
Wha-?!
ぶへえ～ ぐわああ…
Get a good taste of this.
たっぷり味わえ
（団員１）
さすがキャスカ千人長！
Way to go, Commander Casca!
（団員２）しびれました！
You had us mesmerized!
We lost precious time. Let's hurry!
手間取った 急ぐぞ！
（団員１）隊長～ッ
Captain!
加勢します！
We'll assist!
This side first!
（団員２）こっちが先だ！
やめろォ お前らにゃ無理だァ
Stop!
He's too much for you guys!
邪魔なり！
Nuisances!
幕だ 切り込み隊長！
It's over, Captain of the Raiders!
（チューダー兵たち）
うわああ ボスコーン将軍が！
- General Boscogn was...!
- No way!
まさか…
チューダー最強の騎士が…
The strongest knight in Chuder!
あんにゃろ… やりやがった
Damn, he did it!
B-Boscogn!
ボ… ボスコーン
ぬう うろたえるでない！
Do not panic.
He is completely outnumbered!
数で勝るは我が方！
各隊 陣形を…
Get into formation!
（チューダー兵１）何だ？
What is...that banner?!
（チューダー兵２）あの旗は？
（チューダー兵３）そんな バカな
Impossible!
The fortress couldn't have...
（チューダー兵４）まさか城が…
（チューダー兵５）いや あり得ん
No, that can't be!
Idiots, haven't you figured it out yet?
（ガッツ）
まーだ わかんねェのか ボケ！
大将はくたばった 城は落ちた
となりゃあ決まってんだろ
Your general is dead.
Your fortress has fallen.
Isn't it obvious what that spells?
You lost.
負けたんだよ てめえらは！
勝ち鬨だ！
勝ち鬨を上げろ！
Cry out!
Cry out for victory!
ん？ 待ってました！ うお…
I was waiting for that!
Show no mercy if
the enemy offers opposition!
歯向かう敵は容赦するな！
バカモノ！ 誰が引けと言った
Fools! Who ordered you to retreat?!
I am your Supreme Commander!
総大将はこのワシだ
止まらんか！
命令がわからんのか？
Stop, I say!
Follow my orders!
Hey, you! Come back! Come back!
おい 貴様！
戻れ 戻らんかあ！
ぬおっ
（グリフィス）
お久しぶりです ゲノン閣下
It's been a long time,
Lord Gennon.
（ゲノン）おお… グリフィス！
待ちこがれたぞ この時を
Oh!
Griffith! How I have waited
for this moment.
さあ… よく見せてくれ
その顔を…
Come...let me have
a closer look at your face.
その目だ
あの時と少しも変わらぬ その眼差し
Those eyes...
That gaze has not changed
since that time.
What's the matter?
Why are you so quiet?
ど どうした？ なぜ 黙るのだ
敵味方に別れたとはいえ片時も
お前を忘れたことは なかったぞ
We may have parted foes,
but I never forgot about you
for a second.
求めるのは いつもお前の影ばかり
I always looked for your shadow...
のう グリフィ…
Right? Griffi...
グリフィス
Griffith!
Why do you look at me like that?
なぜ そんな目で見る？
まさか 恨んでおるのか このワシを
Don't tell me you resent me?
（グリフィス）
お恨みなどしていませんよ 閣下
I do not resent you, Excellency.
むしろ その逆です
In fact, just the opposite.
あなた一人をたらし込むことで
何百人もの部下を養うことができた
By using you, I was able to provide
for hundreds of my subordinates.
危険な戦場に送ることなく ね
Without having to send them
onto a treacherous battlefield.
あなたは我々の命の恩人ですよ
We all owe you our lives.
ああ… グリフィス お前は…
Griffith, you...!
私の夢にすがる部下に対し
私ができることは ただ一つ
I can only do one thing for
my subordinates who share my dream...
“勝ち続けること”です
そのために手段は選びません
That is to continue winning.
That's why I do not choose the method.
あなたは そんな私の歩く道端に
転がっていた―
You were like a stone lying
by the side of the path I walk.
ただの“石ころ”です
You bastard!
き 貴様ァ
きゃ～！ グリフィス様！
（市民１）鷹の団バンザーイ
Three cheers for
the Band of the Hawk!
（市民２）ミッドランドの守護神様！
The savior of Midland!
Thank you!
We are grateful for your efforts!
（市民３）
ありがとう！ よくやってくれた
Lord Griffith!
（女性たち）
グリフィス様 グリフィス様
Lord Griffith!
- Lord Griffith!
- How handsome!
（ジュドー）カーッ スゲー
Will you look at this?!
ウインダムに
こんなに人がいたんだな
I didn't know so many people
lived in Windham.
Whoa!
よっと！
（他の女性）
あ～ん コルカス様ずるい～ッ
No fair, Corkus!
One at a time. One at a time!
順番 順番
（オカマ）あたしにも～！
Me too!
（女性たち）キャスカ様～！
Miss Casca! Look this way!
（市民４）切り込み隊だ！
Oh! It's the Raiders!
（市民５）ガッツ隊長もいるぞ！
I see Captain Guts too!
（市民６）鷹の団 最強の戦士だ！
He's the strongest warrior
in the Hawks!
Wow... This is amazing!
ひゃー こりゃすげえや
どうです 隊長
手の一つでも振ってみちゃ
How about it, Captain?
Wave to the crowd.
何たって今回の
ヒーローなんですから
You're the hero of this battle,
after all.
隊長
Captain?
Hmm?
（ガストン）
どうしたんですか またボーッとして
What's the matter?
You've been in a daze.
And you've been so quiet, lately.
ここんとこ元気ないみたいっすけど
No, it's nothing.
んなことねーよ こんなの
三年前には誰も考えなかったろうな
Nobody would've thought of
something like this three years ago.
I'll say.
ほんとっすね
俺は 俺の国を手に入れる
I will get my own kingdom...
Nobody but him.
あいつ以外はな
（キャスカ）ありがとう
Thank you.
（コルカス）
ハハハハ こりゃすげえや！
This is amazing!
Oh my, look.
（女性１）まあ ご覧あそばせ
（女性２）鷹の団の方たちじゃ
ありませんこと？
Aren't they from the Band of the Hawk?
（男性）おお
ミッドランドの守護神たちか
Oh, the guardians of Midland!
We have to look sharp,
or they'll make fun of us.
ビシッと決めねえと
なめられるぜ！
（貴婦人１）
お帰りなさいませ グリフィス様
Welcome home, Lord Griffith.
（貴婦人２）
ご案じ申しておりましたわ
We were very worried about you.
（貴婦人３）
私も毎日 お祈りしておりました
I prayed for you every day.
（貴婦人４）ダンスのお相手は
いらっしゃるのですか？
Do you have a dance partner?
（貴婦人５）鷹の団のご活躍話
お聞きしたいですわ
I'd love to hear the exploits of
the Band of the Hawk.
戦の話など野蛮なだけで
退屈ではありませんか？
Won't you get bored listening
to barbaric tales of battle?
（貴婦人６）
そんなこと ありませんわ！
Not at all!
（貴婦人４）とっても刺激的です
They're very stimulating.
He's a natural!
慣れたもんですなー
クーッ 一人くらい
こっちに回してくれ～
Jeez!
He could at least send one our way!
（貴婦人７）
鷹の団の隊長さんたちですね
You're the captains of
the Band of the Hawk, aren't you?
Huh?
戦場での武勇伝 お聞きしたいわ
I'd love to hear
your heroic tales of battle.
You must be so strong.
（貴婦人８）
さぞかし お強いのでしょう
ええ… そりゃもう
Oh well, yes...
（貴婦人９）
んまあ～っ ぜひお話を！
Oh, do regale us.
（コルカス）とても一晩じゃ
語りつくせませんが お時間は？
Oh, I couldn't finish in a single night...
Do you have the time?
（貴婦人９）
たっぷり ありましてよ
All the time in the world.
（貴婦人10）
あなたが切り込み隊長の？
You're the Captain of the Raiders?
一人で百人の敵を倒したって
He slew one hundred of
the enemy by himself.
ほんとにィ！
Really?
あのボスコーン将軍を倒したのも
この方ですわ
He's the one who brought down
General Boscogn too.
んまあ～っ！ グリフィス様と
どちらがお強いのかしら？
Oh my... Who's stronger?
You or Lord Griffith?
（貴婦人10）すごい筋肉！
- Amazing muscles!
- Oh, so hard!
まあ なんて硬いのかしら…
I could fall in love!
（貴婦人11）惚れ惚れしますわ
Oh, how cute...
あら あなた可愛いわ
あなたも鷹の団なの？
Do you belong to
the Band of the Hawk too?
Y-Yes, I do.
は はい 僕も鷹の団…
で その時 襲ってきたのが
ボスコーン将軍率いる…
Then, who should attack but...
The knights led by General Boscogn!
勘弁してくれ…
- Give me a break...
- None other than...
- Hey! No fair, Guts!
- The Holy Purple Rhino...
あ～ ずるいよ ガッツ～！
ったく冗談じゃねえぜ…
You've got to be kidding...
（女性）いえ あたしは…
No, I...
（貴族１）
どなたか先約でも？
Did someone else already ask?
（女性）そ そうなんです
Y-Yes...
（貴族２）
あなたのような女性を放っておく
男性がいるはずありませんからね
No man could possibly ignore
a woman like you.
では その方の後では？
How about after him then?
（貴族３）
いやいや ここはこの私めに…
No, no... I am after him.
（女性）でも…
But...
（貴族３）
あなたにぜひ 私の歌を聞かせたい
I would love to sing for you.
（貴族１）あ ちょっと…
Oh, just a minute...
This is why I hate nobility.
どうして こう貴族ってヤツらは…
おい 協力しろ！
あいつら しつこくて困ってるんだ
Hey, help me.
Those guys won't leave me alone.
あ キャ…
頼む！
Please!
（ガッツ）おい！
Hey!
へえ…
剣を振り回している方が
よっぽど気が楽だ
It's so much easier just
to swing around a sword.
（ガッツ）同感
I agree.
（キャスカ）慣れないことは
するもんじゃないな
We shouldn't do things
we're not used to.
スカートなんて
何年もはいてなかったし
I haven't worn a skirt in years.
And I have all these muscles now.
こんなに筋肉もついちゃった…
おかしいか？ やっぱり…
I look funny, don't I?
Not at all.
結構イケてるぜ
You look pretty good.
ほんとか？
Really?
Yeah.
どうだ？
グリフィスをダンスに誘ってみたら
Why don't you go and
ask Griffith for a dance?
（キャスカ）私なんか
グリフィスの足を踏むのがオチさ…
I'd only step on his toes.
お前こそ どういう心境の変化なんだ
So what made you change?
今まで こんなお堅い場所に
顔を出さなかったじゃないか
You never used to show up
at these stuffy functions.
（ガッツ）
見届けとこうと思ってさ
I thought I'd see it for myself...
Huh?
（ガッツ）グリフィスと鷹の団が
何をやってきたか
I wanted to see just what Griffith and
the Band of the Hawk have accomplished.
あいつが
どれだけのものを手に入れて―
All the things
he's managed to get so far...
そして これから何を
手に入れようとしているのか…
and everything he's going to try
to get from here on out.
ガッツ お前…
Guts, are you...?
もうごめんなんだ あいつの夢の中で
あいつを見上げてるのは…
I've had enough...
of being part of his dream
and looking up at him.
あいつにだけは―
He's the only one...
なめられるわけには いかねえんだ
I can't allow to take me for granted.
お前… まさか
You're...not...
Your Excellency!
皆の者 永きにわたる試練の歳月
まことに大儀であった
Everyone, you have endured well
over these many months of tribulation.
心から礼を言うぞ
You have my sincerest thanks.
As you are aware,
this victory was all due
（国王）皆も知っての通り
この勝利は―
to the work of the Band of the Hawk
led by Count Griffith.
グリフィス卿率いる鷹の団の
活躍によるところが大きい
For nearly 100 years,
この百年 不可能と言われ続けた
ドルドレイ攻略を―
the capture of Doldrey had been
considered an impossible task.
彼らはその類まれなる
勇猛果敢さで成し遂げたのだ
But with great daring and courage,
they accomplished it.
よって余はグリフィス卿と鷹の団に
白鳳騎士団の名を与え―
Thus, I am bestowing the name,
the White Phoenix Knights,
to Count Griffith and
his Band of the Hawk,
千人長諸君には例外なく騎士の称号と
爵位を与えようと思う
the first time such a rank and
honor has been granted.
おお 白鳳将軍
The White Phoenix General!
白鳳騎士団ですって…
The White Phoenix Knights!
Oh my!
まあ
Ridiculous...
バカな
At this rate, they will...
（男性）
これでは ますますヤツらが…
イデデ… やっぱり夢じゃねェ
俺たち貴族なんだァ～！
Ouch...
I'm not dreaming, after all.
We're nobles!
鷹の団バンザ～イ
Hurrah for the Band of the Hawk...!
うう～ さぶ…
It's cold...
ガッツ お前とは
随分ケンカもしたけど―
Guts, we've argued many times,
but we've braved death together.
一緒に死線を越えてきた仲間だろ
鷹の団の苦労もやっと実を結んで
何もかも これからじゃないか
All the hardship the Band of the Hawk
endured is finally paying off.
This is only the beginning.
Why would you...?
それを…
もう 決めちまったことだからな
I've already made up my mind.
だけど…
But...!
ガッツ！
Guts!
抜けるつもりなのか 鷹の団を
You intend on quitting
the Band of the Hawk?
すまねえ
I'm sorry.
（リッケルト）
すまないじゃ わかんないよ
That's not an explanation.
The Band of the Hawk
is your family!
鷹の団はガッツにとっても
家族同然のはずじゃないか
それを捨てていっちゃうほどの
理由って何さ
What reason could you possibly
have to abandon us?
俺たち貴族になれるんだよ？
We can be nobles!
夢のような暮らしを手に入れて
何の不満があるっていうのさ？
We'll be able to live a life
that's straight out of a dream.
What misgivings could you have?!
A grown man made the decision,
so let's respect it.
大の男が決めたことだ
黙って行かせてやろう
（リッケルト）だけど… だけどさあ
みんなだって困るだろ？
But... But...!
You're all against it, aren't you?!
ガッツは鷹の団の要なんだよ
Guts is vital to
the Band of the Hawk!
ケッ！ こいつ一人のせいで
鷹の団が強いわけじゃねえ！
The Band of the Hawk isn't strong
just because of him!
（リッケルト）でも！
But...
おだまりや！
Shut the hell up!
この際だから言っといてやる
This is as good an occasion as any
to say this!
俺はてめえがでえっきれーだったぜ
はなっからな
I've hated you from the very start.
どうして こうもてめえがムカつくのか
今ようやく わかったぜ
And I finally figured out
why you irritate the hell outta me.
その面だよ
It's that face of yours!
Looking so smug...
てめえだけが深刻な悩みを
抱えてるってなその面が―
like you're the only one
who's got serious troubles.
どうしようもなく俺を
イラつかせるんだ！
You really make me sick!
はん！ 大したもんだぜ
He's something else!
俺たちが苦労して
手に入れたものなんざ―
All that we had to endure to
get here means nothing to him.
こいつにとっちゃ
何の価値もねえんだから
ゴミみてえにほっぽり出して
ご大層な苦難の道を歩けばいいさ
So let him throw it all away
like yesterday's trash.
Walk the path of suffering
as much as you want!
好きなだけな
ケッ！ 何を求めてるか知らねえが
てめえはグリフィスにはなれねェ！
I don't know what you're looking for,
but you'll never be Griffith.
Never!
絶対にな！
へっ 今度 戦場で会うことがあったら
背中に気をつけるんだな！
If we ever meet up on the battlefield,
watch your back!
あー すっきりしたぜ
Man, that felt good!
世話になったな みんな…
Thanks for everything, guys.
待って ガッツ
Wait, Guts!
（グリフィス）あの時 言ったはずだ
お前は俺のものだとな
I thought I told you that day...
that you belong to me.
どうしても出て行きたいと
言うのなら―
If you insist on leaving...
wrest yourself away
by your sword.
剣で自分を もぎ取っていけ
グリフィス…
Griffith...
笑って “じゃあな”ってわけには
いかねえのか
So I can't just leave with
a smile and a "take care"?
I guess you mean business.
マジらしいな
待ってよ
仲間同士で斬り合うつもり？
Wait!
You're comrades!
Are you really going to fight?
グリフィスも引き留めるなら
話し合いで
Griffith, if you want to stop him,
talk it through!
キャスカ 邪魔すんじゃねえ
Casca, don't get in our way.
ピピン 何するの 放して
Pippin, what're you doing? Let go!
やるしかないな
There's no other way.
ケッ 腕の一本も斬り落とされりゃ
目が覚めんだろ
Maybe if he gets an arm cut off,
he'll come to his senses.
（キャスカ）みんな
どうしたんだ 止めなきゃ…
What's wrong with all of you?
Stop them!
正規軍のお上品な生活で
忘れちまったのか？
Did the good life in
a real army make you forget?
剣で取られたら剣で取り返す
それが俺たち傭兵の鉄則だろ
If you're taken with a sword,
you take yourself back with a sword.
That's the rule for mercenaries like us.
だけど
But...!
だけど…
But...
（グリフィス）
その夢を踏みにじる者があれば―
...stand against anyone who dares to
trample on it with his body and soul.
全身全霊をかけて立ち向かう
たとえそれが この私でも…
Even if that person is me.
（グリフィス）
行きたいのか そんなに…
Are you so determined...
俺の手の中から…
to leave my grasp?
ダメだ ダメだ
You can't...
You can't!
許さない！
I won't allow it!
Griffith!
グリフィス！
シューッ
じゃあな
Take care.
グリフィス…
Griffith...
ガッツ！
Guts!
ガッツ…
Guts...
（メイド長）当然です 一国の姫が
平民出の殿方に会いに行くなど
Absolutely not!
A princess of a kingdom going out
to meet a gentleman of common birth...?!
（シャルロット）
今のグリフィス様は白鳳将軍
Lord Griffith now is
the General of the White Phoenix!
ミッドランド軍の最高司令官です！
It is the highest rank
in the Midland army!
（メイド長）
それは来月の叙任式を経てからです
That is only after
next month's installation.
さ アンナ
Anna, do keep an eye on her.
くれぐれもご自重くださいませ
もう半年もお会いしていないのよ
せめて…
I haven't seen him in six months.
At least...
せっかく平和になったのに…
Just when we finally have peace...
誰っ？
Who's there?!
Lord Griffith...
グリフィス様
Pardon me...
（グリフィス）失礼
一体 どうなさったのです？
What is the matter?
こんなことが知れたら
大変な騒ぎになりますわ
If anyone discovers you,
there will be such a terrible uproar!
Forgive me...
（グリフィス）すみません
このような非礼…
やはり許されることではありませんね
I suppose this breach of etiquette
is unforgivable.
すぐに…
I'll leave...
お会いしたかった
I've longed to see you.
グリフィス様がご出立されてから
私 ずっと怖くて…
From the moment you left,
I've been so afraid...
戦場から悪い知らせが
届くのではないかと毎日そればかり…
Every day, I dreaded getting word
about you from the battlefield...
I prayed so hard for your well-being.
どれだけ ご無事を
お祈りしたことか…
神が… 願いを
お聞き届けくださったのですわ…
God has answered my prayers.
ごめんなさい…
安心してたら涙が…
Forgive me...
I'm so overcome with relief
that I can't help my tears...
No!
い いや…
怖いの… ですか？
Are you afraid?
あっ いや…
（グリフィス）そう…
何も恐れることはありません…
Yes... There is nothing
to be afraid of.
All the frightening things...
All the sad things...
恐ろしいことも
悲しいことも―
Just cast them into the fire.
皆 火にくべてしまえばいい…
よく降るなァ
It's pouring.
グリフィス見なかった？
Have you seen Griffith?
さあ？ 今日はあれから
見かけないけど
Nah, I haven't seen him since then.
そう…
I see.
Take care...
（ガッツ）じゃあな…
じゃあな… じゃあな… じゃあな…
（隊長）これはこれは誰かと思えば
次期白鳳将軍閣下ではありませぬか
Well, well... If it isn't His Lordship,
the future White Phoenix General.
こんな時間に
どうなされたのですか？
What brings you here
at this early hour?
ここが どなたのお屋敷かは
ご存じでしょうな
You do realize whose palace this is?
事と次第によっては―
There may even be cause
to charge you
ミッドランド王家への
反逆罪もあり得る
with treason against
the Midland's Royal House.
引っ立て～い！
Take him away!
（リッケルト）何だろうね グリフィス
急にこんなところに召集かけてさ
What's up with Griffith?
Making us assemble like this.
軍事教練だろ？ 抜き打ちの…
It's probably a surprise drill.
でも何の装備も いらないって…
But we were told not
to bring any weapons.
（コルカス）
んじゃ野駆けでも やろうってんだろ
It's probably just a jaunt.
Since we beat Chuder,
we haven't been in a decent battle.
そりゃチューダーに勝って このかた
まともに戦はしてねェが―
だからって
こんな日にやらんでもなァ
But of all days...
昨日もとうとう帰ってこなかったし
He didn't return at all yesterday.
やっぱりショックだったのかな
グリフィス
It must've been
a shock to Griffith, after all.
バーカ グリフィスがあんなことで
落ち込むようなタマかよ
Stupid! Something like that
wouldn't bother Griffith.
But...
（リッケルト）だけど…
Just shut up!
（コルカス）うるせーんだよ！
あんなバカ一人 抜けようが
くたばろうが関係あるかって
Who cares if we lose a fool like him?!
グリフィスは救国の英雄なんだぞ
Griffith is a hero
who rescued a nation!
たかが部下一人に
かまってられるかよ バカバカしい
He has no time to bother
with one subordinate!
That's ridiculous.
（リッケルト）だけど…
（コルカス）だけどだけどって…
But...
"But...but!" Stop it!
もういい！
お前は口を開くんじゃねェ
You just keep your mouth shut!
ケッ どいつもこいつも あのバカが
出てってから辛気臭くてたまんねェや
Ever since that guy left,
everyone's been so depressed!
I'm sick of it!
（ジュドー）
それにしても遅いな… グリフィス
Still, Griffith is late.
敵襲！
We're being attacked!
Is this an ambush?!
待ち伏せか！
Damn!
クソッ チューダーの残党か？
Remnants from Chuder?
No, hold on...
いや… 待て
あれは…
They're...!
ミッドランド軍…
The Midland Army!
（国王）
やはり 下賤の血は抗えぬか！
I should have known.
Common birth is something
you cannot change.
あれだけ 目をかけてやったのに
思い上がりおって！
After I favored you,
this is how you pay me back?!
終わりだ！ お前も
仲間も すべて！
It's over for you and your comrades!
It's all over!
（グリフィス）
そうか… おかしいと思っていました
I see. I thought it was strange.
政略結婚は乱世の常… しかし―
Political marriages are
common during wartime.
But there was never talk about
Princess Charlotte getting married.
シャルロット姫には
少しも婚礼の噂がない…
What are you saying...?
な… 何を！
抱きたいのですか シャルロット様を
You wanted to have Charlotte
for yourself.
いえ あなたが抱いて欲しいのでは？
No...
You want her
to have you, isn't that right?
Silence!
黙れ～！
Damn it, we can't die until we find out
what the hell is going on!
クソッ こんなわけわかんねーことで
くたばれるかよ！
ねえ！ 一体どうなってるの
答えてよ グリフィス！
Hey, what's happening?!
Tell us... Griffith...!
固まるな！ 狙い撃ちされるぞ
Don't stay together.
They're aiming for us.
待て コルカス！
散らばってはダメだ
Wait, Corkus!
Don't scatter!
There's no way
we'll break through them alone!
単騎で破れるような
囲みではないぞ
隊列を組め！
Get into formation!
Don't give the enemy any chances!
敵に余裕を与えず
一点突破で脱出する！
We'll attack together
and make a run for it!
- Right!
- Gotcha!
総員 楔形陣形ー
突撃ーっ！
Everyone, get into wedge formation!
Attack!
グリフィス…
Griffith!
（国王）拷問官！
Torturer!
へい
Yes!
Do whatever you wish to this man.
この男を好きにするがよい
ミッドランド王家に仇なす大罪人だ
He has sinned gravely
against Midland's Royal House.
よ… よろしいんで
Y-You're certain?
（国王）ただし殺すことは許さぬ
己が犯した罪の重さを―
However, you must not kill him.
He shall be made to see the gravity
of his crime while he still breathes.
生きながら とくと思い知らせるのだ
Yes!
鷹は地に堕ちた…
二度と飛び立つことはない！
The hawk has fallen to earth.
It will never take flight again.
（拷問官）
ヒ ヒ… すげえな おめえ
You are something else.
これだけ責められて
声一つ たてねえなんて
You've been beaten to a pulp,
yet you haven't uttered a single cry.
オ… オラ感動しただあ
I-I'm really impressed.
Huh?
ん…？ おお 何だこれ
おもしれ！ オラにくれろ
What's this?
That's great! I want it.
ああ… もったいねえ
落としちまったあ…
Ah, what a waste...
I dropped it.